<DMLDOC Sid="DOC" Mfg="SMS"><pmdt><pmid>43896</pmid>
<pmtitle>New York Times (1923-Current file)</pmtitle>
<pmq>New York, N.Y.</pmq>
<issn>03624331</issn>
<srctype>16</srctype>
<esrctype>HISTORICAL NEWSPAPER</esrctype>
</pmdt>
<pcdt><pcid>1576444</pcid>
<pcdtn>19240117</pcdtn>
<pcdta>Jan 17, 1924</pcdta>
</pcdt>
<docdt><docid>101578010</docid>
<copyrt Sid="HNP" Mfg="SMS" Date="20020123" Time="095714">Copyright New York Times Company Jan 17, 1924</copyrt>
<doctitle>COTTON GAIN HALTED BY SALES PRESSURE</doctitle>
<docsubt>Session Ends With the Final Quotations Off 60 to 75 Points. BUYING POWER IS SLIGHT British Cabinet Outlook and French Tax Plan Restraining Factors at Liverpool.</docsubt>
<pgcount>1</pgcount>
<startpg>25</startpg>
<arttyp>article</arttyp>
<docl>English</docl>
<docsec>FIANANCIAL</docsec>
<docmfg>PQID_HNP</docmfg>
</docdt>
<txtdt Sid="HNP" Mfg="SMS" Date="20020123" Time="095714"><text Sid="HNP" Mfg="HNP" Date="20020123" Time="095714"><paragraph>COTTON GAIN HALTED BY SALES PRESSURE</paragraph><paragraph>Session Ends With the Final Quotations Off 60 to 75 Points.</paragraph><paragraph>BUYING POWER IS SLIGHT</paragraph><paragraph>British Cabinet Outlook and French Tax Plan Restraining Factors at Liverpool.</paragraph><paragraph>
Though further covering occurred in cotton during early trading yesterday, the market came under heavy selling pressure later in the session and broke over three-quarters of a cent. While a more favorable Census report than anticipated had caused covering in several directions, the resulting upturn served to bring out contracts rather than stimulate general buying.
</paragraph><paragraph>
Iill demand for actual cotton, as reflected in dally tl- in Southern markets, remains Light and professional        Iment ham been turning against  a -- . A rush to sell in the last hourI used a running decline and disclosed] only a limited buying power. Final]  showed a loss of 60 to 75! . 7hile both Liverpool and &apos;ew Orleans displayed a relatively easier tenden. cy during earlier trading, the covering movement that developed following the Census report on Tuesday continued here and brought a further advance in prices. After a slight setback immediately following the opening, buying order for both ., and / cn ered the ring and absorbed ell      n-ats offered. Several Ltnds of cotton
</paragraph><paragraph>
r  a2 rls!ng:, .and before&apos; the demand coul,$&apos;  y S&apos;old. I ?above 34 cents. .his represented a i galn of a cent in/two days and brought i  to a level where the market ran into a more liberal supply of cotton. Contracts bought at lower figures the previous dar come out when &apos;May was around 34.50 cents and professional operators  a disposition to contest any further advance. Vrth a sharp recovery at a time whe sales of actu/tl cotton are light and  mainly in th way of filling previous  rather than new business, trading was not broad enough to take the cotton for sale and carry on the upward movement at the same time. Liverpool lost part of the advance before the close there,  encouraged realizing as well as professional selling as the morning progressed. UncertaintY over the possible change in the British Cabinet, as well as the manner in which the French Chamber will receive the bill to increase taxation, remained a restraining factor, lew Orleans weakened and a slow decline of 35 points followed. It was not until MarCh sold around 34 cents that the market 3 greater ; resistance and recovered 20  In early afternoon trading, f)n the upturn, however, cotton vas again for sale and the last hour selling pressure caused lowest prices of the day. The fact that Cue report on domestic  had failed to attract outside or trade buying caused  of cotton bought during the morning and lack of buying Dower became evident. Stop-loss orders were encountered during the afternoon and the market lost ground rapidly in final trading. All orders for arch around 34 cents were filled, and when May broke through 34 cents a rush of selling caused a running decline in prices. quantity of wire orders from Southern sources were executed the last fe minutes of the :day, break/ng ]ay  33 cents and over 80 points from best figures of the morning. The market closed at the bottom with Cne selling movement still in evidence. Yesterday&apos;s quotations : Prv. Open. High. Low. Close. Day. i January-. ..... 32.6 34.00 33.70 33.25 33.85 Aarch ........ 24.20 34.36 32.r1 .q?..-3-60 24.21 ]tay .......... $4.: 34.r, .3.70 33.73-0 34.41 July ........ .3.30 33.57 32.f) 32.60-70 33.25 Oct ........... &quot;8.60 2.o 2s.o 28.]0-16 28.*;o December .... 28.10 28.10 27.90 27.65 28.30 The local market for spot cotton wss quiet, 55 points decline, 33.80e for midI  upland. Southern spot markets were: Galveston. 33.70c, 65 points de,c line; Savannah. 83.05e, 86 points decline; Norfolk. 93.3e. 62 points decline
</paragraph><paragraph>
I ;&apos;N 34c .&apos; Uneh&apos; &apos;&apos;;, -- Ohston;.. [33.5c 70  decline.; Little Rock, c, ... . &apos; &apos; I &apos;esterday s  st&amp; were: YesLast &apos; ; Last terday. veek. &apos;ear. , , receipts ...... 21,551 20,332 10,580 [ Exports ......... 6,879 5,466 44,549 EXlorts ...3,598 736 3,463,647 3,070,464 I l-es t ork . 175 N26 177,715 71,682 Fort stocks ....... 1,62i&apos;,084 1,030.689 964.192 24. I&apos;. arrivals... 437 ....... . 7,146 I: Liverpool cables: Spot cotton, more demand. 36 points advance 19.42d for middling. Sales 6,000 bales, of which I American 4,000; imports 33,000, of which American 32,000. Futures Opened steady, 126 to 33 points up hnd closed steady. ][6 to 23 points up.&apos; Prices: Jan. 9.61d I{arch 9.65d, [ay 19.63d, July 19.17d, Oct. 16.60d, ) Manchester -- Yarns moderate demand cloths,doing afair business. SEEK TO STOP STOCK SALE. Inter&apos;national Sliver Co. Shareholders Form Protective Body. Stockholders of the International SLIver Company have received a letter announcing the formation of a Stockholders&apos; Protective Commitee. The  consists of R. D. MeGrath of Lazard -, Arthur Lehman of Lehman Brothers and Sidney C. Borg. The committee, it is said, was formed to prevent the sale of $600,000 additional  common stock by the company at $50 9share. The letter states the Stockholders&apos; Committee obtained an Inunctlon against the directors in selling the  stock, and that as a result the company has withdrawn ,the offer. The  is said to  about two-thirds of the $685,363 common stock of $100 a share par value outstanding. Those in touch with the affairs of the company assert that the recent offering of common stock at $50 a share places a value of $125,000 cash on the $250,000 capital common stock of $100 a share pat&apos; value given to directors for the Colt Arms factory, which the directors had pre  purchased for $125,000. Locomotive Repair List Declines. The railroads of the United States on Jan. I had 10,375 locomotives in need of repair, or 16.1 per cent., a decrease of 498 f-rein the number on Dec. 1.
</paragraph></text>
</txtdt>
<abstracts Sid="HNP" Mfg="SMS" Date="20020123" Time="095714"><short-abs Sid="HNP" Mfg="HNP" Date="20020123" Time="095714"><paragraph>
Though further covering occurred in cotton during early trading yesterday, the market came under heavy selling pressure later in the session and broke over three-quarters of a cent. While a more favorable Census report than anticipated had caused covering in several directions, the resulting upturn served to bring out contracts rather than stimulate general buying.
</paragraph></short-abs>
</abstracts>
<derdt Sid="HNP" Mfg="SMS" Date="20100220" Time="172033"><sort-key>0048A14B0A136EC4085841E10B3069CF</sort-key>
<hit-list-line>COTTON GAIN HALTED BY SALES PRESSURE; Session Ends With the Final Quotations Off 60 to 75 Points. BUYING POWER IS SLIGHT British Cabinet Outlook and French Tax Plan Restraining Factors at Liverpool.; New York Times (1923-Current file)	Jan 17, 1924</hit-list-line>
<word-count>961</word-count>
<dmlversion>PQ6.22/a</dmlversion>
<arttyp>article</arttyp>
</derdt>
</DMLDOC>
